International Workers Order (IWO) Records 5276
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Plays, 1941-1949 (Box 65, Folder 11)
  Includes plays, sample scripts, routine correspondence, some correspondence in Yiddish.
- Plays (Box 36, Folder 1)
- Poems and Songs, 1942-1949 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  Includes program of 25th mid-winter concert; Pageant Jewish Folk Chorus; and (in Yiddish) a song to the Order, tank poems and songs to be delivered at "Ten tanks to Russia".
- Poems and Songs (Box 36, Folder 3)
  In Yiddish. Tank poems and songs for "Ten tanks to Russia".
- Postwar Rebuilding Program - 191946 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  In Yiddish. Includes discussion program, broadening social security, Jewish resettlement problems, Jewish Culture in America lectures.
- Programs, 1944-1947 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  Includes Warsaw Ghetto Program; Passover Program; 15th anniversary of JPFO Program (Yiddish and English); Folklore Program; Chanukah; Emma Lazarus; Washington and Lincoln; I. L. Perez.
- Programs, 1944-1947 (Box 36, Folder 6)
- Radio Scripts, 1942-1946 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  People to Remember series; Our Order; routine correspondence; etc.
- Speaker's Guides (Box 36, Folder 8)
  Outlines and guides on anti-Semitism, Palestine and Zionism, Structure of the Jewish community, Purim, etc.
- Speeches, 1943-1947 (Box 65, Folder 12)
- National School Committee. Minutes of National School and Culture Committee, 1931-1933 (Box 37, Folder 1)
- NSC. Minutes of School Conference held in Camp Kinderland, 1943 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  Yiddish - program, report, speech.
- NSC. Workmen's Circle School Convention - Philadelphia, 1943 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  Yiddish - resolutions, speech.
- NSC. Minutes - National School and Cultural Committee (NSCC), 1943-1949 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  Yiddish - resolutions, speeches, report of teacher conference held in Camp Kinderland.
- NSC. Report of NSCC meetings, 1945 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  Yiddish - includes staff report, Camp Kinderland report, theatre ensemble report, article, speech.
- NSC. NSCC 9th Convention of Schools, 1949-1950 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  Yiddish - includes ideas for agenda, delegate form, reports, program plan.
- NSC. Minutes of meetings of NSCC, 1949-1950 (Box 37, Folder 7)
- NSC. Correspondence, 1938 (Box 37.1, Folder 1)
  I. Goldberg correspondence, mostly routine, re publications: Proletarische Derziung and Yungvarg.
- NSC. Correspondence, 1938 (Box 37.1, Folder 2)
- NSC. Correspondence, 1938 (Box 37.1, Folder 3)
  In Yiddish. Re changing name of publication from Proletarische Derziung to Haim un Derziung, and routine.
- NSC. Correspondence, 1938 (Box 37.1, Folder 4)
- NSC. Correspondence, 1939 (Box 37.1, Folder 5)
  Routine re publications - I. Goldberg and Synoptic translation of "Home and Education," January 1939; and articles for Haim un Derziung.
- NSC. Correspondence, 1939 (Box 37.1, Folder 6)
- NSC. Correspondence, 1938-1939 (Box 37.1, Folder 7)
  In Yiddish. Re Haim un Derziung, receipts, collection notices, book orders, etc.
- NSC. Correspondence, 1938-1939 (Box 37.1, Folder 8)
- National School Committee. Correspondence, 1940-1942 (Box 37.1, Folder 9)
  Includes letter form Sadie Doroshkin, State Secretary, California District, JPFO, to S. Davidovich and reply re problems with schools; Dr. Levine's qualifications as a teacher being questioned by Jewish Education Bureau; I. Goldberg routine (Yiddish).
- NSC. Correspondence, 1942 (Box 37.1, Folder 10)
  In Yiddish. Includes responses to letters from I. Goldberg and Sandler re openings and closings of schools, teacher appointments, draft deferments, also correspondence from Preble and Chefetz re Chicago Schools.
- NSC. Correspondence, 1942 (Box 37.1, Folder 11)
- NSC. Correspondence, 1939-1944 (Box 37.1, Folder 12)
  I. Goldberg letters to teachers re hiring and firing and routine. In Yiddish.
- NSC. Correspondence, 1944-1946 (Box 65, Folder 14)
  form letter re 1st May, Warsaw ghetto, million dollar campaign; letter to Saltzman re new book, routine; letter to Marc Chagall acknowledging book Brenendiger Licht and other routine; letter from Corporal W. Saltzman to I. Goldberg re his views on the war
- NSC. Correspondence, 1947-1948 (Box 65, Folder 15)
  In Yiddish. To Marc Chagall re Bayla Chagall's 2nd book; to prospective member that there is no danger in joining the JPFO; and routine.
- NSC. Correspondence, 1949 (Box 38, Folder 1)
- NSC. Correspondence, 1948-1949 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  Letter to S. Davidovich from Estelle Thomas in Poland re pen-pals; letter to S. Davidovich from George Starr and reply re Peretz, Cheifitz and problems in the Chicago schools; letter from Sadie Doroshkin to I. Goldberg and written copy of phone reply re S
- NSC. Correspondence, 1945-1950 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  Form letters re meetings, salaries, attacks of Jewish reactionaries, loss of right to teach in public schools, organized committees to remove children from the schools, fund raising, convention (English and Yiddish); and I. Goldberg's resignation from Nat
- National Schools Committee. Correspondence, 1940-1952 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  In Yiddish. Re publications of JPFO.
- NSC. Correspondence, 1947-1956 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  Routine and news of Supreme Court appeal hopes to cancel liquidation order.
- NSC. Correspondence, 1950-1956 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  Routine re California Schools, and letter from I. Goldberg to Mrs. Marovitch describing curriculum in schools.
- NSC. Correspondence (Box 38, Folder 7)
  Brief history of Camp Kinderland; memo on the schools of the JPFO, 4 pages; listing of schools in New York City area; and routine.
- NSC. Correspondence - Boston District, 1937-1950 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  In Yiddish. Re teachers pay meetings, routine with I. Goldberg, S. Davidovich, Sonia Sokol, Jack Weinman; English language clippings and letter (7/20/49) re attack on Chelsea school being Communist, by Jack Weinman, teacher, Chelsea Jewish Children's School
- NSC. Correspondence - Boston District, 1937-1950 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  In Yiddish. Re teachers pay meetings, routine with I. Goldberg, S. Davidovitch, Sonia Sokol, Jack Weinman; English language clippings and letter (7/20/49) re attack on Chelsea school being Communist, by Jack Weinman, teacher, Chelsea Jewish Children's School
- NSC. Correspondence - The Bronx, 1939-1950 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  In Yiddish. Routine.
- NSC. Correspondence - Brooklyn, 1948-1950 (Box 38, Folder 11)
  In Yiddish. S. Davidovitch and I. Goldberg correspondence re distribution of Yungvarg; description of Brooklyn schools; and routine.
- NSC. Correspondence - Chicago, 1943-1944 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  In Yiddish. Correspondence from I. Goldberg re teacher negotiations and routine.
- NSC. Correspondence - Chicago, 1943-1944 (Box 38, Folder 13)
- NSC. Correspondence - Chicago, 1943-1950 (Box 38, Folder 14)
  In Yiddish. Correspondence from G. Sandler, S. Davidovitch re more teachers needed and routine.
- NSC. Correspondence - Cleveland, 1950 (Box 38.1, Folder 1)
  In Yiddish. Correspondence with I. Goldberg, S. Davidovitch re camp for children, teachers' salaries, Yungvarg distribution, increasing school attendance and routine.
- National School Committee. Correspondence - Los Angeles, 1942 (Box 38.1, Folder 2)
  In Yiddish. Correspondence to Paver, Maymudes, Lottie Moloch, Zelig Zipper re articles for publication, membership drives, complaints in teachers' salaries, argument between Lottie Moloch and Z. Zipper and routine.
- National School Committee. Correspondence - Los Angeles, 1942 (Box 38.1, Folder 3)
- NSC. Correspondence - Montreal, 1942-1944 (Box 38.1, Folder 4)
  I. Goldberg routine correspondence.
- NSC. Correspondence - Montreal, 1942-1944 (Box 38.1, Folder 5)
- NSC. Financial, 1935-1944 (Box 38.1, Folder 6)
  Routine financial material including bills, receipts, ledger sheets of various schools.
- NSC. Financial, 1935-1944 (Box 38.1, Folder 7)
- NSC. Financial, 1935-1944 (Box 38.1, Folder 8)
- NSC. Financial, 1935-1944 (Box 65, Folder 16)
- NSC. Financial, 1935-1944 (Box 65, Folder 17)
- NSC. Financial, 1935-1945 (Box 38.2, Folder 1)
  Routine financial including bills, receipts, ledger sheets, routine financial correspondence.
- NSC. Financial, 1935-1945 (Box 38.2, Folder 2)
- NSC. Financial, 1935-1945 (Box 38.2, Folder 3)
- NSC. Financial, 1935-1945 (Box 38.2, Folder 4)
- NSC. Financial, 1935-1945 (Box 38.2, Folder 5)
- NSC. Financial, 1935-1945 (Box 38.2, Folder 6)
- NSC. Financial, 1935-1945 (Box 38.2, Folder 7)
- NSC. Financial, 1935-1945 (Box 38.2, Folder 8)
- NSC. Financial, 1935-1945 (Box 38.2, Folder 9)
- NSC. Financial, 1935-1945 (Box 38.2, Folder 10)
- NSC. Financial, 1935-1945 (Box 38.2, Folder 11)
- NSC. Financial, 1935-1945 (Box 38.2, Folder 12)
- NSC. Financial, 1935-1945 (Box 38.2, Folder 13)
- NSC. Financial, 1935-1945 (Box 38.2, Folder 14)
- NSC. Financial, 1935-1945 (Box 38.2, Folder 15)
- NSC. Financial, 1935-1945 (Box 38.2, Folder 16)
- NSC. Financial, 1935-1945 (Box 38.2, Folder 17)
- NSC. Financial, 1937-1949 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  Routine financial including bills, receipts, ledger sheets and routine correspondence.
- NSC. Financial, 1937-1949 (Box 39, Folder 2)
- NSC. Financial, 1937-1949 (Box 39, Folder 3)
- NSC. Financial, 1937-1949 (Box 39, Folder 4)
- NSC. Financial, 1937-1949 (Box 39, Folder 5)
- NSC. Financial, 1937-1949 (Box 39, Folder 6)
- NSC. Financial, 1937-1949 (Box 39, Folder 7)
- NSC. Financial, 1937-1949 (Box 39, Folder 8)
- NSC. Financial, 1937-1949 (Box 39, Folder 9)
- NSC. Financial, 1937-1949 (Box 39, Folder 10)
- NSC. Financial, 1937-1949 (Box 39, Folder 11)
- NSC. Financial, 1937-1949 (Box 65, Folder 18)
- NSC. Financial, 1937-1949 (Box 65, Folder 19)
- NSC. Financial, 1937-1949 (Box 65, Folder 20)
- NSC. Financial, 1937-1949 (Box 66, Folder 1)
- NSC. Financial, 1937-1949 (Box 66, Folder 2)
- NSC. Financial, 1937-1949 (Box 66, Folder 3)
- NSC. Classroom Materials, 1942-1945 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  In Yiddish and English. Posters; materials for observance of Week of Sorrow and Protest and Purim carnival; routine correspondence; United Nations pamphlets; study guides; workbooks, Jewish history, bulletin, speech and lecture notes; lecture re use of Je
- NSC. Classroom Materials (Box 40, Folder 2)
  In Yiddish. Composition projects for elementary and high schools, test.
- NSC. Essay Contest, 1948 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  Essay contest entries.
- NSC. Essay Contest, 1948 (Box 40, Folder 4)
- NSC. Essay Contest, 1948 (Box 40, Folder 5)
- NSC. General Information, 1949-1951 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  In Yiddish and English. List of how many schools in each district, lists of Educational Directors in Brooklyn District and Schools in New York, brief history and outline of JPFO schools.
- NSC. May Day, 1941-1950 (Box 66, Folder 4)
  Form letters and program. Yiddish
- NSC. Mendele Moicher Storm, 1947 (Box 66, Folder 5)
  Speaker's Guide.
- National School Committee. Miscellaneous, 1941-1950 (Box 66, Folder 6)
  In Yiddish. News article reply to attack on JPFO Schools by New York Board of Education; news release; insurance policy; minutes of Teacher Committee on JPFO Schools; school publications weekly report, report cards.
- NSC. Miscellaneous (Box 66, Folder 7)
  Exams from children's schools (Yiddish).
- NSC. Miscellaneous (Box 66, Folder 8)
- NSC. New York City - Legal, 1948-1949 (Box 40.1, Folder 1)
  Court documents re Board of Education of the City of New York denying the use of public school buildings for the conduct of classes or lectures to the National School Committee of the JPFO; also pamphlet "i am a Jewish child"; pamphlet "The Law and Rules
- NSC. New York City - Legal, 1948-1949 (Box 40.1, Folder 2)
- NSC. Teacher Personal Fact Sheets, 1946-1947 (Box 40.1, Folder 3)
  In Yiddish. Includes also inspection visit report - JPFO schools.
- NSC. Training School, 1948-1952 (Box 40.1, Folder 4)
  Form letter announcing a national leadership training school at Camp Kinderland,; daily schedule; student roster; applications; correspondence to Sam Pevzner re training school from Sol Rotenberg, Samuel Cheifetz, handwritten notes.
- NSC. Universal Jewish Encyclopedia, 1942-1943 (Box 40.1, Folder 5)
  Includes description of encyclopedia and price; routine correspondence; news release.
- NSC. Yungvarg (monthly magazine), 1940-1943 (Box 40.1, Folder 6)
  Articles and miscellany; statement of ownership; bills; proofs; photographs; etc.
- NSC. Yungvarg (monthly magazine), 1940-1943 (Box 40.1, Folder 7)
- NSC. Yungvarg (monthly magazine), 1940-1943 (Box 40.1, Folder 8)
- NSC. Yungvarg, 1941-1945 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  Articles and miscellany, bills, proofs, photographs, etc.
- NSC. Yungvarg, 1941-1945 (Box 41, Folder 2)
- NSC. Yungvarg, 1941-1945 (Box 41, Folder 3)
- NSC. Yungvarg, 1941-1945 (Box 41, Folder 4)
- NSC. Yungvarg, 1941-1945 (Box 41, Folder 5)
- NSC. Yungvarg - Article on I. L. Peretz (Box 41, Folder 6)
- NSC. Yungvarg, 1943 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  In Yiddish. Articles and miscellany.
- NSC. Yungvarg, 1943 (Box 41, Folder 8)
- Almanac - 1944 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  Routine correspondence re photos and articles for the Almanac.
- American Committee of Jewish Writers, Artists and Scientists, Inc., 1946 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  (R. Saltzman, member of the Joint Executive Committee) - correspondence and form letters re funds for Black Book Committee, rally arrangements and other routine; clipping entitled "Anti-Sovietism and Anti-Semitism, Text of Speech by Albert E. Kahn, Madison
- American Jewish Committee, 1946-1951 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  2 issues - May and August 1946 of The Committee Reporter, published by the American Jewish Committee; memo re: Analysis of New York State - IWO Liquidation, 1951, 5 pages.
- American Jewish Conference - Correspondence, 1943 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  Correspondence re discrimination against JPFO lodges by American Jewish Conference - not invited to participate in Conference; request to become affiliated with the American Jewish Assembly and reply from the Assembly denying membership - much correspondence
- American Jewish Conference - Correspondence, 1945 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  Correspondence re request for JPFO representation on the Interim Committee of the American Jewish Conference; fund raising and routine.
- American Jewish Conference - Correspondence, 1947 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  2 page "Statement on the Scope and Purpose of the American Jewish Conference" by Albert Kahn and Rubin Saltzman; death of Henry Monsky, Chairman of American Jewish Conference; form letters and routine.
- American Jewish Conference - Correspondence, 1948 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  Correspondence re defense of the Jews in Palestine; organization of proposed American Jewish Assembly; financial status; list of members; re conference ceased to function.
- American Jewish Conference - Miscellaneous, 1943-1948 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  Includes delegates lists; 2 page statement "The Future of the American Jewish Conference"; and other miscellaneous documents.
- American Jewish Conference - Publications, 1943-1948 (Box 42, Folder 9)
  Miscellaneous clippings; publications; releases.
- American Jewish Conference (Box 42, Folder 10)
  In Yiddish. Unable to translate.
- American Jewish Congress - Correspondence, 1946-1948 (Box 42, Folder 11)
  Includes constitution (1946) and routine correspondence.
- American Jewish Congress, 1946-1949 (Box 42, Folder 12)
  Includes form letters; clippings; brochures; reports; minutes; "Program Notes"; an appeal by R. Saltzman re expulsion of JPFO from AJC; Spotlight, published by Committee for a Democratic American Jewish Congress; and miscellaneous.
- American Jewish Congress, 1946-1949 (Box 42, Folder 13)
- American Jewish Congress, 1946-1949 (Box 66, Folder 9)
- American Jewish Labor Council, 1948 (Box 66, Folder 10)
  2 page statement "American Jewish Labor Council Statement on Contributions and Activities Within the Last 3 Months."
- Anti-Semitism - Press Releases, 1944 (Box 66, Folder 11)
  2 releases.
- Book League of the JPFO, 1940-1949 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  Includes routine correspondence and 1 bound volume ledger of Yiddish Cooperative Book League.
- Camp Kinderland, 1943-1950 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  List of "Camp Committee"; programs; correspondence; list of "interracial camps"; form letters; financial data; student roster; and routine.
- Camps (Box 43, Folder 3)
  Form letter describing Camp Nitgedaiget.
- Cemetery Department, 1950-1953 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  Includes correspondence, blank forms, lists of cemeteries, financial statements, form letter describing benefits to members, 2 page "Rules Governing Funerals, Graves Used and Reserved on Our Cemeteries in New York and Vicinity"; and miscellaneous.
- Children's Anti-Nazi Protest Meeting, 1943 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  Includes clippings and miscellaneous documents.
- Civilian Defense, 1941-1942 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  Bulletins.
- Committees for the Protection of Foreign Born (Box 43, Folder 7)
  Clippings; articles; mimeographs; broadside.
- The Day, 1948-1951 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  Correspondence re the newspaper refusing to publish JPFO ad.
- Denikin - General (Box 43, Folder 9)
  2 page "Memorandum to State Department on Expulsion of Denikin."
- Germany, 1950-1952 (Box 43, Folder 10)
  Clippings; handwritten notes; broadside; articles.
- Haim un Derziung, 1942 (Box 43, Folder 11)
  Yiddish - apparently articles for the publication.
- Independent Workmen's Circle (Box 43, Folder 12)
  3 page "Statement of the United National Committee to the Injuction Executive of the Independent Workmen's Circle"; excerpts from "50 Years of the Workmen's Circle in Jewish Life" by J. S. Hertz, 4 pages, n.d.
- Israel, 1946-1948 (Box 67, Folder 1)
  Releases, resolutions, correspondence re Israel.
- Jewish Anti-Fascist Committee in the USSR, 1943 (Box 67, Folder 2)
  Letter thanking JPFO members for the hospitality shown while in the United States.
- Jewish Fraternal Home Committee, 1951-1952 (Box 67, Folder 3)
  Form letter; minutes of a conference called by Board of Directors for Jewish People's Home; financial data; speech; reports; agreement to buy Ridgefield Country Lodge, Ridgefield, Connecticut.
- Korea, 1950-1952 (Box 67, Folder 4)
  Mostly newspaper clippings re Korean War.
- Los Angeles Jewish Community, 1949 (Box 67, Folder 5)
  Broadside re Los Angeles Jewish Community Council moving to expel the JPFO.
- Leadership School, 1949 (Box 67, Folder 6)
  Lists; agenda; leaflet re softball tournament; proposed budget for National Junior Leadership School at Camp Kinderland; school announcements; schedule; outline; and miscellaneous.
- Medem, Gina, 1946-1950 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  In Yiddish. Re distribution, advertisement, publication, etc. of Wanderings and Meetings by Gina Medem
- Membership - Drives, 1946-1950 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  Re JPFO's successful membership drive; newsletters; "Facts for JPFO Builders".
- Membership - Dues, 1952-1953 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  Correspondence re dues lists; form letters; lists; G. Sandler correspondence stressing importance of maintaining membership.
- Membership - Dues, 1952-1953 (Box 44, Folder 3a)
- Membership - Reinstatements - Correspondence, 1946-1953 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  Routine correspondence from G. Sandler re reinstating expelled members; form letters from IWO General Secretary Peter Shipka re dues, standing of members and importance of reinstating members in light of the liquidation proceedings; also R. Saltzman correspondence
- Membership - Reinstatements - Correspondence, 1946-1953 (Box 44, Folder 5)
- Membership - Reinstatements - Correspondence, 1946-1953 (Box 44, Folder 6)
- Membership - Reinstatements, 1951-1953 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  Reinstatement lists including lodge number, membership, suspensions, expulsions
- Membership - Reinstatements, 1951-1953 (Box 44, Folder 8)
- Membership - Reinstatements, 1951-1953 (Box 67, Folder 7)
- Miscellaneous, 1944-1953 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  Includes newspaper clippings; office staff medical questionnaires; resolution to save the Office of Price Administration (OPA); legislative and political action newsletter re OPA; Dumbarton Oaks Proposals, broadsides; Earl Browder speech re Freiheit; "Jew
- Miscellaneous, 1946 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  In Yiddish. Correspondence re Cuban contact; thank you from Polish Jewish Organization; establishment of refugee colony in Belgium.
- National Conference of Christians and Jews, 1947-1948 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  Plays; brochure on American Brotherhood Week; program guide "for Brotherhood U.S.A."
- Photographs - Miscellaneous - Yiddish Correspondence., 1942 (Box 45, Folder 4)
- Relief - Rehabilitation Fund, 1946-1951 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  Bills; letter from June Gordon, President, Emma Lazarus Division, JPFO, to Brother Raishi re foster parents plan; "Help! Rehabilitate the Jewish People" outline and material on the million dollar relief and rehabilitation drive of the JPFO, 15 pages; form
- Relief and Rehabilitation Fund, 1946 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  In Yiddish and English. Correspondence re children's home in Paris and summer camps; financial request from Warsaw to support rebuilding; clippings; questionnaires; and routine.
- Relief and Rehabilitation Fund, 1946 (Box 45, Folder 7)
- Rosenberg Case, 1952-1953 (Box 45, Folder 8)
  Petitions for clemency for the Rosenbergs; broadsides; newspaper clippings; handwritten notes; form letters; miscellaneous.
- Russia - Articles and Poetry (Box 45.1, Folder 1)
  In Yiddish. Articles for publication in Unzer Vort Journal sent in by Hebrew Anti-Fascist League of USSR.
- Russia - Articles and Poetry (Box 45.1, Folder 2)
- Russia - Articles and Poetry (Box 45.1, Folder 3)
- Russia - Articles and Poetry (Box 45.1, Folder 4)
- Russia - Campaign Against Soviet Propaganda, 1942-1943 (Box 45.1, Folder 5)
  newspaper clippings re Ehrlich-Alter case; press releases; government document re anti-discrimination (Yiddish and English).
- Russia - Stories About, 1946 (Box 45.1, Folder 6)
- Social Security Campaign, 1945-1947 (Box 45.1, Folder 7)
  Summary of Conference on Social Security in Washington, D.C., by IWO, 11/25-26/45; memo; statement by E. Rymer.
- Soviet-Jewish Life, 1940-1944 (Box 45.1, Folder 8)
  In Yiddish. Bibliography; news clippings; articles; correspondence from Medem.
- Ten Tanks to the Red Army Campaign, 1942 (Box 45.1, Folder 9)
  English and Yiddish. Bulletin, brochures, "What Russia Means to Us" by Albert Einstein, 2 pages; "An Appeal to New England Jewry!" by IWO Jewish Section, 2 pages; broadsides re sending tanks to Red Army to fight Hitler; broadside.
- War and Relief Publicity Material, 1944-1949 (Box 67, Folder 8)
  English and Yiddish. Correspondence from soldiers re war effort and thanks for gifts; new clippings; letters of thanks from war relief organizations
- War Service Campaign Ads, 1943 (Box 67, Folder 9)
  In Yiddish. Proofs; copy of letter from British Embassy on behalf of Winston Churchill thanking IWO for sending him a copy of Wallace's "Century of Common Man."
- Warsaw Ghetto, 1943-1947 (Box 67, Folder 10)
  In Yiddish. News clippings; news release; poems; program for remembrance - copy in English of "Lest We Forget," 1943, 40 pages, compilation of reports received by World Jewish Congress.
- Women's Clubs, 1941-1944 (Box 67, Folder 11)
  In Yiddish and English. Correspondence re various activities including aid to strikers at Dertog newspaper and Transport Workers Strike; support of anti-discrimination bill and routine.
- Women's Clubs - Speeches (Box 67, Folder 12)
  In Yiddish. Speech on women's role in purpose and Society of Women's Clubs including women at work and home; political and economic rights; woman in USSR.
- Zionism, 1951 (Box 67, Folder 13)
  Newspaper clippings and articles.
- The America of Despair (Box 46, Folder 1)
- American Intervention in Greece (Box 46, Folder 2)
- The American Jewish Conference (Jewish Assembly) (Box 46, Folder 3)
- American Policy in Greece (Box 46, Folder 4)
- Ask Hannah (Box 46, Folder 5)
- Belgium at War (Box 46, Folder 6)